<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Visveswaran Vaidyanathan</title><link>https://www.vvisveswaran.xyz/</link><description>Recent content on Visveswaran Vaidyanathan</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 20:30:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.vvisveswaran.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About me</title><link>https://www.vvisveswaran.xyz/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.vvisveswaran.xyz/about/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With over 20 years of experience in tech, Visveswaran is passionate about helping organisations apply SOLID, Lean, Agile, DevOps &amp;amp; SRE principles to achieve meaningful and tangible digital transformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having led teams large and small in diverse areas such as Core Banking, RegTech, GovTech , FinTech and Reliability Engineering, Visveswaran brings a wealth of knowledge and experience with a constant eye towards the big picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visveswaran holds a Masters degrees in IT and business management. During his free time, he enjoys working on side projects and coding for fun, most recently with Rust.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Automating Your Hugo Blog: GitHub Pages Deployment &amp; Playwright Testing</title><link>https://www.vvisveswaran.xyz/blog/github-pages-and-playwright/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 20:30:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.vvisveswaran.xyz/blog/github-pages-and-playwright/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Building a personal portfolio or blog is a rite of passage for many developers. I recently rebuilt my site using &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/"&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;, a fantastic static site generator known for its speed and flexibility. But hosting the code is only half the battle. I wanted a modern CI/CD pipeline that would:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automatically deploy&lt;/strong&gt; my site to GitHub Pages whenever I push to &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automatically test&lt;/strong&gt; my site to ensure I haven&amp;rsquo;t broken anything before merging changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through how I set up this automated workflow using &lt;strong&gt;GitHub Actions&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Playwright&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Beginner's Guide to Programming Languages</title><link>https://www.vvisveswaran.xyz/blog/20240502t082832/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 09:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.vvisveswaran.xyz/blog/20240502t082832/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Programming is a valuable skill across many industries and professions today. This guide will introduce you to four popular programming languages—Java, Python, JavaScript, and Ruby—highlighting their unique features, applications, and why they are great choices for beginners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="java"&gt;Java&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Java, developed by Sun Microsystems in the mid-90s, is a robust, object-oriented language. It’s designed to be portable across multiple platforms, meaning Java programs can run on any device that has the Java Virtual Machine (JVM) installed. This &amp;ldquo;write once, run anywhere&amp;rdquo; philosophy makes it a popular choice for developers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Purpose</title><link>https://www.vvisveswaran.xyz/blog/20240502t082704/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 08:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.vvisveswaran.xyz/blog/20240502t082704/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I get this question from my friends when I pitch the idea of a Blog &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are a lot of blogs available in the internet. Why another one ??&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comming from a small town in Southern India I learnt to program from a young age. I was learning GW BASIC for a good 6 years. That was from Standard 6 all the way till Standard 12. Back them computers were inducted into the schools as a curriculum. Where students had to remove their shoes and go next to a &lt;em&gt;very costly machine&lt;/em&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>